Contact

230 N 6th St #711 7578803239 (Mobile) kyle@ohboyohboyohboy.org

www.linkedin.com/in/kyle-yetter (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Node.js React.js Amazon Web Services (AWS)

Languages

French (Elementary) French (Elementary)

Kyle Yetter

Senior Software Engineer at Wonolo

Richmond, Virginia, United States

Summary

I am an experienced software engineer specializing in programming with modern languages such as Ruby, Javascript, and Python. My career spans many years across gig economy markets, education tech, web hosting, and telecommunication. I have developed a broad spectrum of technical knowledge with the keen creative problemsolving skills that make for the best engineers. I take pride in my work, and I value the quality of results. I am seeking placement with a team of other talented professionals where I can exercise the full strength of my abilities.

Experience

Wonolo Senior Software Engineer II June 2022 - April 2023 (11 months) San Francisco Bay Area

Stack technologies: Ruby, Rails, Postgresql, GraphQL, Apache Airflow, Python, React, Redis

- * Worked closely with the Trust and Safety team to integrate Wonolo's data with Unit21, a fraud detection and case management system
- * Designed and maintained Apache Airflow DAGs to synchronize live application data, warehoused data, and real-time user events with third-party integrations
- * Maintained the Wonolo admin site and fielded improvements for support agents and internal customers
- * Researched and proposed tooling improvements for the core Rails build
- * Performed the initial design and established the foundation for a customerfacing public GraphQL API

TaskRabbit Senior Software Engineer December 2018 - April 2022 (3 years 5 months) Richmond, Virginia Area

- * Built foundational platform for company integration with Twilio Segment.

 Used this to establish tooling integrations for marketplace Operations teams.
- * Researched and designed GraphQL API for use by the mobile and web apps.
- * Led many projects to serve the work of other departments inside the company
- * Mentored junior engineers and worked extensively to transfer knowledge.
- * Provided server-side engineering support for TaskRabbit's mobile and web apps.
- * Wrote a regular series of articles with tips and advice on Ruby programming.
- * Conducted screenings and interviews of engineering candidates.

eBackpack, Inc.
Senior Software Developer
September 2013 - December 2018 (5 years 4 months)
Yorktown, VA

- * Perform development and maintenance on a fully-featured Learning Management System (LMS) platform targeting K-12 schools
- * Plan and document high-level feature and product implementations
- * Handle dev-ops activities and management on a fleet of application servers and other company equipment
- * Design and implement cross-platform web and mobile UI with Angular and other modern Javascript and HTML tools
- * Coordinate responsibilities with a small team of developers

InMotion Hosting

2 years 7 months

Developer

July 2012 - September 2013 (1 year 3 months)

- * Performed development and maintenance on company's account management website using agile techniques
- * Lead planning, design, and implementation on key company development projects
- * Spearheaded initiatives to improve maintainability and flexibility of company's code base through advanced OOP techniques
- * Authored extensive documentation targeted for a variety of audiences within the company
- * Worked closely with other developers to maintain an efficient, productive, and stable team work environment

Systems Administrator III

December 2011 - July 2012 (8 months)

- * Planned network systems and strategized to maximize hosting up-time for all customers
- * Developed thorough and efficient solutions to problems impacting customer quality of service
- * Designed and maintained server-side software for system maintenance, auditing, and customer-facing functionality in Perl, PHP, and Python
- * Participated in a 24-hour "on call" rotation system with other senior administrators to handle any system emergencies outside normal work hours
- * Safeguarded company network from security threats and combated cyber attacks

Systems Administrator II

March 2011 - December 2011 (10 months)

- * Ensured the responsiveness and availability of web hosting services for customers
- * Worked with customers directly to manage and improve resource usage of hosting accounts

Sprint

Managed Network Services Technician II May 2006 - March 2008 (1 year 11 months)

- * Conducted thorough troubleshooting of outages within the private networks of client companies
- * Provided concise summaries of issues for review by management and customers

Education

University of Virginia

BS, Electrical, Electronics and Communications Engineering · (2001 - 2005)